Guide to the Brooks McNamara Papers MSS.162
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Subject Files
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1989-1994, Rockettes Easter Extravaganza]: Programs. (Box 30, Folder 515)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1985-1993, Rockettes Christmas Spectacular]: Programs. (Box 30, Folder 516)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, Siegfried and Roy]: Programs., undated (Box 30, Folder 517)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Radio City Music Hall misc.]: Pamphlets, calendars., undated (Box 30, Folder 518)
  - Vaudeville VIII: Course syllabus, conference program, "Vaudeville," play script by Laurence Carr., undated (Box 31, Folder 519)
  - Vaudeville IX: Proposal to NEH for a "Survey of Vaudeville Performance on Film"., 1995 (Box 31, Folder 520)
  - Vaudeville IX: Articles, correspondence, student work, bibliographies., 1978-1995 (Box 31, Folder 521)
  - Vaudeville X: Edited draft of introduction., 1987 (Box 31, Folder 522)
  - Vaudeville XI [misc.]: Correspondence, photocopy, student work., 1970, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 523)
  - Ventriloquism: Student work, correspondence, fliers., 1976, 1989, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 524)
  - [Virtual Vietnam]: Clipping., 1994 (Box 31, Folder 525)
  - [Washington Square Players]: Article., 1965 (Box 31, Folder 526)
  - Weird Stuff: Clippings, articles, photocopies, postcards, pamphlets, fliers, correspondence, ephemera., undated (Box 31, Folder 527)
  - Weird Stuff: Clippings., undated (Box 31, Folder 528)
  - [Welfare State International]: Brochure., undated (Box 31, Folder 529)
  - Wild West Show: Clippings, articles, photocopies, programs, postcards, bibliographies, student work., undated (Box 31, Folder 530)
  - Oscar Wilde: Drafts of paper, "Oscar Wilde and the Aesthetes.", undated (Box 31, Folder 531)
  - Bert Williams: Photocopies relating to "In Dahomey: a Negro Musical Comedy.", undated (Box 31, Folder 532)
  - [Women in Performance]: Photocopy., undated (Box 31, Folder 533)
  - Worker's Theater I: Articles., undated (Box 31, Folder 534)
  - Worker's Theater II: Articles, photocopies., undated (Box 31, Folder 535)
  - World's Fairs: Clippings, bibliography, postcards., undated (Box 31, Folder 536)
  - Yiddish Theatre: Clippings, programs., undated (Box 31, Folder 537)
  - Environmental (incl. restorations, role playing, etc.) [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Folk and Festival [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Med. [medicine] Show [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Melo. and Spect. [melodrama and spectacle] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Minstrelsy [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Moral and Ed., Ents. [educational entertainments] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Musical Th. [theater] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Parade and Pag. [pageant], I [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Day of Jubilee [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - R3 Shoulder [film], 1918 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Coney Island [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - The Cake Eater reel [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - Good Old Five Cent Trolley Ride [film], 1905 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - The Making of Broncho Billy [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Gullse's Wayward Path [film], 1915 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Malkasian [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Abbot & Costello "Who's on first" [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - R-1 Shoulder Arms [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - The St. James Mime [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Deadly Turning [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Malkasian [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Making a Living [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Grit of Girl Telegrapher [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - The Vagabond [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 20-21)
  - Lonedale Operator [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Golden Age of the Theatre [sic] from Audio Rarities 2465 [audio], undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Vi-Ton-Ka [audio], 1983 (Box 37, Folder 24-25)
  - A National Theater: Interviews with Charles Dillingham A.C.I., San Francisco; Rudolph Bing, Metropolitan Opera, N.Y.; by Douglas Amir [sic] [audio], 1972 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Inteview: Jerome Lawrence by Seth Glassman [audio], 1972 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - The Mummy's Tomb [audio], undated (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Vitoaka [audio], 1983 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Yip Harburg: The Fellow Who Followed a Dream (NPR Journal, Spring 1981) [audiocassette] (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Gershwin Festival at Guild Hall "Love, Money, and Politics..." [audiocassette], 1986 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Gershwin Festival At Guild Hall: Classical and Classic [audiocassette], undated (Box 37, Folder 32-33)
  - Brooks McNamara slides [DVD-R], undated (Box 37, Folder 34-35)
  - Brooks McNamara Broadway Theaters [DVD-R], undated (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Parade and Pag. [pageant] II [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Parl. and Op. and Mech. [parlor and optical and mechanical] [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Theatres [sic], I [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - Theatres [sic] B'way [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - B'way, II [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
  - Tent Show and Tom [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Tournament [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Vaude [vaudeville] and Music Hall [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Sildes - Holding File, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Misc. [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
- Series II: Printed Materials.
  Scope and Contents note
  Series II consists of a small number of books that accompany McNamara's subject files [7 folders].
  - Brown, Wesley. Darktown Strutters: a novel. New York: Cane Hill Press, 1994. (Box 31, Folder 538)
  - [Program:] Gloucester Tercentenary Pageant. Presented at Stage Fort Park, Gloucester, MA. August 28th and 30th, 1923. (Box 31, Folder 539)
  - Elliott, Eugene Clinton. A History of Variety-Vaudeville in Seattle: From the Beginning to 1914. Seattle: University of Washington Press, 1944. (Box 31, Folder 540)
  - McEvoy, Harry K. Knife Throwing: a Practical Guide. Tokyo, Japan; Rutland, VT, USA: Charles E. Tuttle Co., 1977. (Box 31, Folder 541)
  - Brooks, Peter F. Pearly Kings and Queens in Britain. London: Barry Rose Publishers, n.d., undated (Box 31, Folder 542)
  - Mellor, G.J. Pom-Poms and Ruffles: The Story of Northern Seaside Entertainment. Yorkshire: Dalesman Publishing Company, Ltd., 1966. Clipping found inside the book, "Seasider's Diary: Confirming Blackpool's status," Evening Gazette, November 23, 1974., 1966, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 543)
  - MacKaye, Percy. The Roll Call: A Masque of the Red Cross. Washington, D.C.: National Headquarters American Red Cross, 1918. Copy from Glenn M. Loney. (Box 31, Folder 544)
- Series III: Talks, Papers.
  Series III: Drafts, manuscripts, and notes for published papers and articles, as well as printouts for talks and speaking engagements [76 folders].
  - Brooks, M - Writings [unsorted]: BM notes, drafts, syllabi, photocopies., undated (Box 31, Folder 545)
  - American Political Theatre - Talk: BM drafts., undated (Box 31, Folder 546)
  - Edwin Booth's Legacy: Issue of journal, Nineteenth Century Theatre, vol.21, no.2 (Winter 1993). (Box 31, Folder 547)
  - B.T.I. Introduction (Botto, Louis): BM introduction to Louis Botto, 2 pages., undated (Box 31, Folder 548)
  - Burlingame Intro.: BM drafts of introduction to Lloyd Burlingame, 4 pages; invitation., undated (Box 31, Folder 549)
  - The Busker: Photocopy of BM article; Newsletter of the Greater London Arts Association (September/October 1975). (Box 31, Folder 550)
  - The Busker in London a Hundred Years Ago: BM draft., undated (Box 31, Folder 551)
  - A Carnival City: Exhibition catalog, "The Country Fair Carnival: Where the Midway Meets the Grange," Chemung County Historical Society, Elmira, NY (1992). (Box 31, Folder 552)
  - Catfish Dreamin': BM draft, "Catfish Dreamin' Meets the Medicine Show and Other Traditional Dreams and Illusions.", undated (Box 31, Folder 553)
  - Celebrate Broadway Talk: Draft., undated (Box 31, Folder 554)
  - The Circus and the New Theatre: Photocopies of BM article in Theatre Crafts (September 1972). (Box 31, Folder 555)
  - Civic Pageantry in New York City: BM paper draft., undated (Box 31, Folder 556)
  - Come on Over: BM article, "Come on Over: The rise and fall of the American amusement park," in Theatre Crafts (September 1977). (Box 31, Folder 557)
  - A Congress of Wonders: BM article, "A Congress of Wonders: the Rise and Fall of the Dime Museum," in ESQ: A Journal of the American Renaissance (1974). (Box 31, Folder 558)
  - David Douglass: Photocopy of BM article, "David Douglass and the Beginnings of American Theatre Architecture.", 1968 (Box 31, Folder 559)
  - Owen Davis and the Shubert Brothers: BM article in the newsletter of the Shubert Archive., 1995 (Box 31, Folder 560)
  - Deco Talk: BM draft of talk at the Lyceum Theatre., undated (Box 31, Folder 561)
  - Defining Popular Entertainment: Drafts of BM keynote speech for the International Symposium on Popular Entertainment, CUNY Graduate Center, 1987. (Box 31, Folder 562)
  - Defining Popular Culture: BM article in Theatre History Studies volume 18 (1998). (Box 31, Folder 563)
  - Double Gothic: the Scenography of Michael Kirby, an interview by Brooks McNamara: Photocopy of article in Theatre Design and Technology (Winter 1979). (Box 31, Folder 564)
  - The English Playhouse in eighteenth-century America: Photocopy of BM article in The Connoisseur (September 1967). (Box 31, Folder 565)
  - Environmental Theatre: BM notes, drafts, course materials., undated (Box 31, Folder 566)
  - Feasts and Processions in the Urban Environment: BM article manuscript and photocopies., undated (Box 31, Folder 567)
  - Films and Touring Films (Talk): BM talk, 3 pages., undated (Box 31, Folder 568)
  - For Laughing Purposes Only: BM draft and photocopy of article, "For Laughing Purposes Only": The Literature of Popular Entertainment., undated (Box 31, Folder 569)
  - "Friends of the Library" Speech: BM draft., undated (Box 32, Folder 570)
  - "I'm Dr. Kronkhite."…: Drafts of BM talk, "I'm Dr. Kronkhite." "I'm Dubious.": The Health Professional in American Popular Comedy; poster for event (1987). (Box 32, Folder 571)
  - The Invisible Theatre: BM drafts and photocopy of article, "The Invisible Theatre: The Folk and Festival Tradition in America.", 1978 (Box 32, Folder 572)
  - Jews and the American Theatre - Talk: BM drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 573)
  - Kirby Memorial Service - Speech: BM drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 574)
  - Living Over the Store: BM drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 575)
  - Forward, Carol Martin's book: BM drafts, correspondence, and photocopy., 1993, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 576)
  - David Mayer Introduction: BM draft, 2 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 577)
  - The Medicine Show: BM article from program book, Festival of American Folklife, Smithsonian Institution (1979). (Box 32, Folder 578)
  - The American Medicine Show (Exhibit): Exhibition catalogue, The American Medicine Show, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, December 1983 to February 1984; January 1984 issue of the Yale Weekly Bulletin and Calendar., 1983-1984 (Box 32, Folder 579)
  - The Medicine Show Log: Photocopy of BM article, "The Medicine Show Log: Reconstructing a Traditional American Entertainment.", 1984 (Box 32, Folder 580)
  - Medicine Show Performance: Playbill, poster., undated (Box 32, Folder 581)
  - The Indian Medicine Show: Photocopy of BM article., 1971 (Box 32, Folder 582)
  - Lecturing to Accompany Paintings and Other Exhibits: Draft of BM talk, 3 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 583)
  - Step Right Up (dust jacket), undated (Box 32, Folder 584)
  - Step Right Up (2nd edition advertisement), undated (Box 32, Folder 585)
  - "Talking": BM draft, 50 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 586)
  - Up in All the Acts and Bits: Souvenir program for The Vi-ton-ka Medicine Show, and photocopy of BM article., 1983 (Box 32, Folder 587)
  - "You Are All Dying": Issue of journal Listening: Journal of Religion and Culture (1987) with BM article, "You Are All Dying": Illness and Death in the American Medicine Show; correspondence, photocopy. (Box 32, Folder 588)
  - TDR: Memoires of the Mouthpiece: Photocopies., 1986 (Box 32, Folder 589)
  - The Pageant Era: Issue of Theatre Crafts, Bicentennial Special Issue: History on Outdoor Stages (September 1975); photocopies. (Box 32, Folder 590)
  - Parody in Traditional American Entertainments: BM drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 591)
  - The Paterson Strike: BM article, "Paterson Strike Pageant," in TDR (Summer 1971)., 1975 (Box 32, Folder 592)
  - Performance Space: the Environmental Tradition: BM article in Architectural Association Quarterly (April/June 1975). (Box 32, Folder 593)
  - Performance Studies…: BM talks and notes on the history and definition of Performance Studies., undated (Box 32, Folder 594)
  - Popular Entertainment and the Community: BM draft., undated (Box 32, Folder 595)
  - Popular Entertainment program at N.Y. State Museum, undated (Box 32, Folder 596)
  - Popular Scenography: Photocopy of BM article., 1974 (Box 32, Folder 597)
  - An Interview with Percy Press: Photocopy of BM article, "An Interview with Percy Press and A Portfolio of Buskers.", 1975 (Box 32, Folder 598)
  - Public Celebrations in 19th century NY: BM draft., undated (Box 32, Folder 599)
  - Reviews, Etc.: Articles, photocopies, reviews, clippings., undated (Box 32, Folder 600)
  - Reviews of Books: Clippings, articles, drafts, correspondence., undated (Box 32, Folder 601)
  - Day of Jubilee - Reviews and Nominations, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 602)
  - St. Patrick's Day - Talk: BM draft, 19 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 603)
  - "Scavengers of the Amusement World": BM article, "Scavengers of the Amusement World": Popular Entertainment and the Birth of the Movies, in exhibition catalogue, American Pastimes, Brockton Art Center - Fuller Memorial, Brockton, MA, January - April 1977. (Box 32, Folder 604)
  - Scene Design and Early Film: BM draft and photocopy of article., 1986 (Box 32, Folder 605)
  - Shubert Archive: Clippings, articles, photocopies, newsletters; BM draft; interview with Donald Flamm., undated (Box 32, Folder 606)
  - Sam Shubert, Producer: BM draft, 16 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 607)
  - The Shuberts and "The Gladiola Girl": BM draft, 4 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 608)
  - The Shubert Brothers and the "Box-Office" Play: BM drafts, article published in Shubert Archive newsletter (1992) and LMDA Review (vol.5, no.1). (Box 32, Folder 609)
  - The Shuberts as Theatre Builders: Draft, 15 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 610)
  - Shubert Archive Talk; Shubert Musicals Talk: BM drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 611)
  - "Something Glorious": BM drafts, notes, photocopies of article, "'Something Glorious': Greenwich Village and the Theater.", 1993 (Box 32, Folder 612)
  - The Stratford Jubilee: Photocopy of BM article, "'The Stratford Jubilee': Dram to Garrick's Vanity.", 1962 (Box 32, Folder 613)
  - Stuart Sherman's Third Spectacle: Draft and photocopy of BM article., 1976 (Box 32, Folder 614)
  - Tales from the Salesman's Golden Age: BM article in issue of TWA Ambassador: The Trans World Magazine (October 1975). (Box 32, Folder 615)
  - Tamiment Playhouse: Draft of talk., undated (Box 32, Folder 616)
  - "Theater" entry - Americana Annual, 1973: Clippings, photocopies, correspondence, BM notes and drafts, undated (Box 32, Folder 617)
  - Theatre, American: BM draft, 17 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 618)
  - Vessel: The Scenography of Meredith Monk (Interview): BM article in TDR (March 1972), photocopies., 1972, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 619)
  - Virtual Fantasies Forward: BM draft, 2 pages., undated (Box 32, Folder 620)
  - What Makes Theater?: BM article in Oculus, a publication by the American Institute of Architects, New York Chapter (June 1996). (Box 32, Folder 621)
- Series IV: Anthologies [source materials].
  Series IV: Materials such as clippings, photocopied articles, notes, scripts, and correspondence relating to McNamara's Anthology of Popular Entertainments, as well as a British Play Anthology (1990) [21 folders.]
  - Anthology - misc. outtakes, etc.: Photocopies, articles, scripts, drafts., undated (Box 32, Folder 622)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [I. Overview and Introduction]: Draft, correspondence, clipping, BM notes., 1989-1991 (Box 32, Folder 623)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [II. What the Butler Saw, 1969]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 624)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [III. The Changing Room, 1971]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 625)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [IV: Plenty, April 1978]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 626)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [V: Betrayal, November 1978]: Clippings, photocopies., 1980s (Box 32, Folder 627)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VI: Nicholas Nickelby, opening 1980]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 628)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VII: Pack of Lies, 1983]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 629)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VIII: Theatre General]: Clippings, photocopies., undated (Box 32, Folder 630)
  - P.E. Anthology: BM draft of his edited volume, American Popular Entertainments: Jokes, Monologues, Bits and Sketches., 1983 (Box 32, Folder 631)
  - Scenes (Acts, Bits, Etc.) D.: Scripts, photocopies, correspondence., undated (Box 32, Folder 632)
  - "Brooks' Copy" [Jokes]: Scripts, photocopies, drafts., undated (Box 33, Folder 633)
  - Brooks' Material for Matt Silverstein: Student work, bibliographies., 1972, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 634)
  - American Popular Entertainments [Book Draft, March 1983]: Drafts, correspondence. (Box 33, Folder 635)
  - Scetch Material: Photocopies, scripts., undated (Box 33, Folder 636)
  - Jokes and Related Material: Draft, correspondence., undated (Box 33, Folder 637)
  - Jokes, Quips, Rhymes, Comedy Songs, Comedy Dialogues; A.: Correspondence, scripts., undated (Box 33, Folder 638)
  - Jokes Material: Articles, photocopies, scripts, notes, correspondence., undated (Box 33, Folder 639)
  - Speeches, Recitations, Lectures, Pitches: Photocopies, drafts., undated (Box 33, Folder 640)
  - Merry Muldoons, 1991 Revision: Clippings, articles, reviews, advertisements, correspondence, BM drafts and notes. (Box 33, Folder 641)
  - Miscellaneous - undated: Clippings, articles, photocopies, correspondence, bibliographies. (Box 33, Folder 642)
- Series V: Plays, written with Laurence Senelick.
  Series V: Drafts and source materials for plays [8 folders].
  - Diary of a Provincial Lady, Final Copy: Drafts., 1984 (Box 33, Folder 643)
  - Mayhew's London, 3/22/84, Draft: Drafts, photocopies., 1984 (Box 33, Folder 644)
  - The London Poor: Draft., undated (Box 33, Folder 645)
  - The London Poor (Through Darkest London) [series]: Drafts., 1984 (Box 33, Folder 646)
  - Through Darkest London: Draft., 1983 (Box 33, Folder 647)
  - Through Darkest London - publicity slides, fliers, photos, programs., undated (Box 33, Folder 648)
  - Hiss the Villain, by Michael Booth: Photocopy., 1964 (Box 33, Folder 649)
  - Twentieth Century by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur: Script., undated (Box 33, Folder 650)
- Series VI: Course Materials and Student Papers.
  Series VI: Course materials and student work.
  Although Series VI contains types of materials that are also located throughout Series I and filed thematically under specific subject headings, this box was originally separate and is organized more generally.
  - Interviews: Student interviews with popular performers., undated (Box 33, Folder 651)
  - American Theatre/Film (SP '88): Bibliography., 1988 (Box 34, Folder 652)
  - Course Materials: Photocopies, articles, bibliographies, notes., undated (Box 34, Folder 653)
  - Course Materials: Photocopies, article, fliers, newsletters, bibliographies, notes., 1995, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 654)
  - Course Materials: Programs, newsletters, publishers book catalogues; spring 1996 issue of "The Threshers' Review: a Magazine for Midwest Old Threshers.", 1994-1996 (Box 34, Folder 655)
  - Course Materials: Clippings, articles, photocopies, photographs, programs, newsletters, publishers book catalogues, undated (Box 34, Folder 656)
  - Folk Festival Course (general): Course syllabi, correspondence, photocopies., 1991, 1992. (Box 34, Folder 657)
  - Courses (unsorted): Photocopies, articles, correspondence, syllabi, bibliographies, BM notes, undated (Box 34, Folder 658)
  - Radical and Experimental Course: Articles, photocopies, course syllabus, BM notes, student paper., 1991-1992 (Box 34, Folder 659)
  - Print Catalogues: Clippings, articles, publication and print catalogues., undated (Box 34, Folder 660)
  - Radio - 1930s: BM notes, photocopied book chapters., undated (Box 34, Folder 661)
  - Schechner Collection - Princeton: Princeton University Library Chronicle (Autumn 1993). (Box 34, Folder 662)
  - Senelick, Laurence: Articles., 1991, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 663)
  - Student Papers (1972-1992, undated) (Box 34, Folder 664)
  - Student Paper (1972-1996, undated) (Box 34, Folder 665)
  - Student Papers (1973, 1992, undated) (Box 34, Folder 666)
  - Student Papers (1972-1988, undated) (Box 34, Folder 667)
  - NYU Thesis: Court Theatre 1980-1981, Susan Weinacht (Box 34, Folder 668)
  - Student Papers (1991-1996) (Box 34, Folder 669)
  - Student Papers (1973-1996) (Box 34, Folder 670)
  - Student Papers (1973-1989) (Box 34, Folder 671)
  - Student Papers (1980-1996) (Box 34, Folder 672)
  - Student Papers [misc.], undated (Box 34, Folder 673)